beatlesbible.com 2019-09-27

# Privacy policy – The Beatles Bible

The Beatles Bible takes your privacy seriously. This privacy policy describes what personal information we collect and how we use it.

Detailed information is further down the page. **Firstly, a jargon-free note from Joe, the site creator:**

This site uses various scripts and tracking mechanisms. However, absolutely no personal information is collected and retained by me. You will never be contacted by this site as a result of visiting, unless you get in touch yourself and your message requires a response. In honesty, I'd rather spend my time writing about The Beatles than crunching visitor data to devise complex and devious marketing strategies. I'm not even very good at the latter.

The tracking is used mainly for stats collection ( **WordPress** and **Google Analytics** ), to indicate which countries visitors are coming from, which pages are the most popular, how long people spend on the site and how many pages they click on. I don't really know much more than that; nor do I need to. I certainly don't know your name, phone number, email or postal address, shoe size or political persuasion.[](https://www.ezoic.com/what-is-ezoic/)

It is also used by third parties for advertising, which helps keep the ship afloat. There's more detail on this below.

There are social sharing buttons which have to connect to your accounts to work, otherwise nothing can be shared. I don't get to see who you are or which pages you like, although I'm very grateful if you choose to share my content with others. The aforementioned services may use cookies to track browser behaviour, but these are not set by the Beatles Bible.

There are options to subscribe to keep up-to-date via Twitter, Facebook or email. These are all third-party facilities and are optional, but please check the privacy policies of those sites if you're concerned about what they do. Again, I don't know who you are unless you choose to tell me (with the exception of Twitter, as a list of [people following my account](https://twitter.com/beatlesbible/followers) is publicly accessible).

The adverts on this site primarily come from Google, Amazon and iTunes. The first two of these uses targeting advertising to display appropriate content related to your browsing history. Again, I don't see or keep any of this information.

You can use adblockers or noscript add-ons, though I'd prefer you didn't. Please be aware that the Beatles Bible depends on advertising revenue to exist. This site is not a big business – there is no multi-millionaire backer, just one person sharing his Beatles knowledge with the world. I love good web content as much as you do, but if everyone blocked the display of advertisements this site – and many others – would no ezlonger be sustainable and its closure would be likely. I have tried to make the adverts as unobtrusive as possible, and have no plans to use popups, overlays or other annoyances.

 **TL;DR:** I'm more interested in The Beatles than I am in spamming or tracking visitors to this site.

 **Sincerely,  
Joe  
www.beatlesbible.com**

What follows is more of a standard message to comply with various legal requirements.

* * *

#### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymised string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is [available here](https://automattic.com/privacy/). After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

#### Routine information collection

All web servers track basic information about their visitors. This information includes, but is not limited to, IP addresses, browser details, timestamps and referring pages. None of this information can personally identify specific visitors to this site. The information is tracked for routine administration and maintenance purposes.

Visitor comments and forum registrations may additionally be checked through an automated spam detection service.

#### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

#### How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognise and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (most likely for the [Fab Forum](https://www.beatlesbible.com/forum/)), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (they cannot change their username, but may set a different display name). Website administrators can also see and edit the same information as users.

#### Controlling your privacy

Note that you can change your browser settings to disable cookies if you have privacy concerns. Disabling cookies for all sites is not recommended as it may interfere with your use of some sites. The best option is to disable or enable cookies on a per-site basis. Consult your browser documentation for instructions on how to block cookies and other tracking mechanism.

#### What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

#### Ezoic partnership

We use [Ezoic](https://www.ezoic.com/)'s [Ad Tester](https://www.ezoic.com/ad-tester-details/) service, which allows online publishers to perform automated ad testing using machine learning. Ezoic tests ad locations, sizes, colors, types and more, then learns and personalises ad combinations to each visitor.

A percentage of Beatles Bible visitors will view pages which are subject to Ezoic's ad testing. They will see adverts in a variety of positions on the page, which over time enables us to improve the balance between revenue (to keep the site afloat) and usability.

You can [view Ezoic's own privacy policy at this link](https://g.ezoic.net/privacy/beatlesbible.com).

#### Cookies and web beacons

GDPR requires that we give visitors the ability to change or withdraw the consent they have provided you. We provide a link [at the top of this page](https://g.ezoic.net/privacy/beatlesbible.com) which enables users to change their choices.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select "Remember Me", your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

Where necessary, The Beatles Bible uses cookies to store information about a visitor's preferences and history in order to better serve the visitor and/or present the visitor with customized content.

Advertising partners and other third parties may also use cookies, scripts and/or web beacons to track visitors to our site in order to display advertisements and other useful information. Such tracking is done directly by the third parties through their own servers and is subject to their own privacy policies.

Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on this site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to visitors based on their visit to this site and others on the internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.co.uk/privacy_ads.html "Google ad and content network privacy policy"). Cookies from other third-party vendors may also be used to serve ads on this site.

Some other advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. These partners might include (NB not all are in use – this is a standard disclaimer):

  * Google Adsense
  * Commission Junction
  * Widget Bucks
  * Adbrite
  * Clickban
  * Epic/Azoogle
  * Chitika
  * Linkshare
  * Amazon
  * Kontera
  * Advertising.com
  * CPAStorm
  * Burst
  * Valueclick
  * InfoLinks
  * Vibrant Media
  * 24/7 Real Media
  * Tribal Fusion
  * Casale
  * Tremor Media
  * Adify

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on beatlesbible.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or web beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and/or to personalise the advertising content that you see.

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (eg click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioural advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit networkadvertising.org.

The Beatles Bible has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. The Beatles Bible's privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. [Click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) if you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options.

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways (NB not all of these are relevant to this site):

• To personalise your experience  
(your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs)

• To improve our website  
(we continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you)

• To process transactions  
Your information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason whatsoever, without your consent, other than for the express purpose of delivering the purchased product or service requested.

• To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature

If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.

#### How do we protect your information?

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you access your personal information.

#### Do we disclose any information to outside parties?

Other than described in this privacy policy, we do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety.

#### Third party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

#### California Online Privacy Protection Act compliance

Because we value your privacy we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. We therefore will not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent.

#### Online privacy policy only

This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our website and not to information collected offline.

#### Your consent

By using our site, you consent to this privacy policy.

#### Changes to our privacy policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page.
